{ "questions":[
    {
        "qnumber": 1,
        "question": "According to the framework that defines product innovations, there is an incremental innovation when:",
        "answers": [
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are reinforced",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are reinforced"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are reinforced"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 2,
        "question": "According to the framework that defines product innovations, there is an architectural innovation when:",
        "answers": [
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are reinforced",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are reinforced"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are reinforced"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 3,
        "question": "According to the framework that defines product innovations, there is a modular innovation when:",
        "answers": [
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are reinforced",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are reinforced"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are substituted"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 4,
        "question": "According to the framework that defines product innovations, there is a radical innovation when:",
        "answers": [
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are reinforced",
            "Architecture Relations are unchanged, and Knowledge Components are substituted",
            "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are reinforced"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Architecture Relations are altered, and Knowledge Components are substituted"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 5,
        "question": "In the competitive strategy, the question \u201cWho are our customers?\u201d is connected to the following strategic dimension:",
        "answers": [
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Product leadership",
            "Operational excellence",
            "It is connected to all of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Customer intimacy"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 6,
        "question": "In the competitive strategy, the question \u201cWhat do we offer them?\u201d is connected to the following strategic dimension:",
        "answers": [
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Product leadership",
            "Operational excellence",
            "It is connected to all of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Product leadership"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 7,
        "question": "In the competitive strategy, the question \u201cHow can we deliver it effectively and efficiently?\u201d is connected to the following strategic dimension:",
        "answers": [
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Product leadership",
            "Operational excellence",
            "It is connected to all of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Operational excellence"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 8,
        "question": "Which of these is not a source of strategic innovation?",
        "answers": [
            "Design-Driven innovation",
            "Technology Push innovation",
            "Market Pull innovation",
            "Data-Driven innovation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Data-Driven innovation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 9,
        "question": "Defining the target market and identifying consumer unfulfilled needs allows companies to pursue a:",
        "answers": [
            "Desgin-Driven innovation",
            "Technology Push innovation",
            "Market Pull innovation",
            "None of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Market Pull innovation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 10,
        "question": "Developing innovative products or services and providing a unique meaning to existing goods enables companies to pursue a:",
        "answers": [
            "Design-Driven innovation",
            "Technology Push innovation",
            "Market Pull innovation",
            "None of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Design-Driven innovation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 11,
        "question": "Optimizing production processes and developing new products to satisfy previously unidentified consumer needs allows companies to pursue a:",
        "answers": [
            "Desgin-driven innovation",
            "Technology push innovation",
            "Market pull innovation",
            "None of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Technology push innovation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 12,
        "question": "Ecosystem partners are:",
        "answers": [
            "Organizations weakly interconnected with each other, although dependent on each other for their survival",
            "Artists, cultural organizations, sociologists, anthropologists, marketing and media expert who explore socio-cultural trends",
            "Producers of innovative as well as professional machinery and plants that lead to the identification of technology trends in terms of production processes",
            "Manufacturers of hardware and software components who contribute to identifying digital trends"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Organizations weakly interconnected with each other, although dependent on each other for their survival"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 13,
        "question": "If a company decides to serve a tribe:",
        "answers": [
            "It doesn\u2019t distinguish customers based on their demographic geographic and behavioral characteristics",
            "It brings together two or more distinct but interdependent customer groups though a digital platform",
            "It identifies various customer groups based on their passions, interests and experiences that make them capable of collective action",
            "It distinguishes each customer each customer from others, exploiting the possibilities offered by Industry 4.0"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It identifies various customer groups based on their passions, interests and experiences that make them capable of collective action"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 14,
        "question": "Which of these is not a Building Block of the Business Model Canvas?",
        "answers": [
            "Society",
            "Products",
            "Technology",
            "Resources"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Technology"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 15,
        "question": "Which tool can be used to verify whether a company is strategically aligned in all its strategic dimensions?",
        "answers": [
            "The business model framework",
            "The business model canvas",
            "The digital operating model",
            "The strategic fit matrix"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The strategic fit matrix"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 16,
        "question": "What type of production is carried out in the 1st Industrial Revolution?",
        "answers": [
            "Flexible production",
            "Mass production",
            "Centralized production",
            "Intelligent production"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Centralized production"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 17,
        "question": "What type of production is carried out in the 2nd Industrial Revolution?",
        "answers": [
            "Flexible production",
            "Mass production",
            "Centralized production",
            "Intelligent production"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Mass production"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 18,
        "question": "What type of production is carried out in the 3rd Industrial Revolution?",
        "answers": [
            "Flexible production",
            "Mass production",
            "Centralized production",
            "Intelligent production"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Flexible production"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 19,
        "question": "What type of production is carried out in the 4th Industrial Revolution?",
        "answers": [
            "Flexible production",
            "Mass production",
            "Centralized production",
            "Intelligent production"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Intelligent production"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 20,
        "question": "Which are the generic technological strategies?",
        "answers": [
            "Openness and closure",
            "Complexification and simplification",
            "Usability and security",
            "None of the answer is correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Openness and closure"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 21,
        "question": "Some operational objectives related to the \u201copenness and freedom of system\u201d strategy are:",
        "answers": [
            "Complexification, ownership and flexibility",
            "Centralization, predictability and efficiency",
            "Reactivity, automation and simplification",
            "Decentralization, interoperability and augmentation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Decentralization, interoperability and augmentation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 22,
        "question": "Some operational objectives related to the \u201cclosure and control of the system\u201d strategy are:",
        "answers": [
            "Complexification, ownership and flexibility",
            "Centralization, predictability and efficiency",
            "Reactivity, automation and simplification",
            "Decentralization, interoperability and augmentation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reactivity, automation and simplification"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 23,
        "question": "Which of the following is not one of the nine digital paradigms?",
        "answers": [
            "Digital manufacturing",
            "Cloud Computing",
            "Artificial Intelligence",
            "Cyber Security"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Artificial Intelligence"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 24,
        "question": "Which of the following is not one of the nine digital paradigms?",
        "answers": [
            "Industrial Internet of Things",
            "Blockchain",
            "Big Data Analytics",
            "System integration"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Blockchain"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 25,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Digital Manufacturing paradigm impact the internalization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the optimal size of production sites (reduces economies of scale)",
            "Reduction in the use of unskilled labour and, therefore, the convenience of low-cost relocation strategies",
            "Reduction in the time and costs (transport, warehouse and customs duties) of delivering products to the customer",
            "Increase in external collaboration in product design"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the use of unskilled labour and, therefore, the convenience of low-cost relocation strategies"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 26,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Digital Manufacturing paradigm impact the ownership strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the number of suppliers, in particular, those specialized in the production of complex parts (self-production of components)",
            "Increase in external collaboration in product design",
            "Increase in the creation of products  with new features",
            "Increase in product customization"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the number of suppliers, in particular, those specialized in the production of complex parts (self-production of components)"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 27,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Digital Manufacturing paradigm impact the efficiency strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the optimal size of production sites (reduces economies of scale)",
            "Reduction in product development time and costs (time-to-market and learning economies)",
            "Reduction in the number of items in stock (elimination of components for products, self-production of some components)",
            "Increase in freedom in product design by fostering individual creativity and the birth of new ideas"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the number of items in stock (elimination of components for products, self-production of some components)"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 28,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Digital Manufacturing paradigm impact the flexibility strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the use of unskilled labour and, therefore, the convenience of low cost relocation strategies",
            "Reduction in the number of items in stock (elimination of components for products, self-production of some components)",
            "Reduction in the time and costs (including customs) of procurement (self-production of some components)",
            "Reduction in assembly costs (fewer components)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the use of unskilled labour and, therefore, the convenience of low cost relocation strategies"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 29,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Autonomous and Collaborative Robots paradigm impact the externalization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in efficiency and effectiveness in production planning and control",
            "Possibility to enable complex processing optimizing process variables (machine learning)",
            "Increase in labour productivity by promoting human-to machine interaction",
            "Possibility to enable decentralized production control"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Possibility to enable decentralized production control"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 30,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Autonomous and Collaborative Robots paradigm impact the automation strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in efficiency and effectiveness in production planning and control",
            "Increase in labour productivity by promoting human-to -machine interaction",
            "Increase in the optimization of just-in-time and just-in-sequence deliveries",
            "Increase in product customization"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in efficiency and effectiveness in production planning and control"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 31,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Autonomous and Collaborative Robots paradigm impact the augmentation strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in flexibility without compromising the quality of the work",
            "Possibility to enable complex processing by simplifying human activities",
            "Increase in labour productivity by promoting human-to-machine interaction",
            "Possibility to enable decentralized production control"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in labour productivity by promoting human-to-machine interaction"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 32,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Autonomous and Collaborative Robots paradigm impact the decentralization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Possibility to enable complex processing optimizing process variables (machine learning)",
            "Possibility to enable decentralized production control",
            "Increase in the optimization of just-in-time and just-in-sequence deliveries",
            "Increase in production customization"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Possibility to enable decentralized production control"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 33,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Autonomous and Collaborative Robots paradigm impact the simplification strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Possibility to enable the replacement of human operators in repetitive, strenuous, and risky activities",
            "Possibility to enable complex processing optimizing process variables (machine learning)",
            "Increase in the accuracy of the assembly simplifying human activities",
            "Increase in product customization"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the accuracy of the assembly simplifying human activities"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 34,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Augmented and Virtual Reality paradigm impact the externalization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in training time for new and seasonal workers",
            "Increase in quality control",
            "Reduction in repair times through guided maintenance procedures",
            "Opportunity to enable the possibility of making aesthetic and functional product tests with customers"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Opportunity to enable the possibility of making aesthetic and functional product tests with\r\ncustomers"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 35,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Augmented and Virtual Reality paradigm have an impact on the reactivity strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Opportunity to enable safer and more controlled training environment for workers",
            "Increase in the conformity of the goods taken from the warehouse with what is requested",
            "Reduction in repair times through guided maintenance procedures",
            "Increase in the customer experience"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in repair times through guided maintenance procedures"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 36,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Augmented and Virtual Reality paradigm impact the efficiency strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in the accuracy in the location of the goods stock",
            "Opportunity to enable new forms of human-to-machine interaction in production and maintenance processes",
            "Opportunity to enable the possibility of making aesthetic and functional product tests with customers",
            "Increase in the customer experience"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the accuracy in the location of the goods stock"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 37,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Augmented and Virtual Reality paradigm impact the flexibility strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in training time for new and seasonal workers",
            "Opportunity to enable new forms of human-to-machine interaction in production and maintenance processes",
            "Reduction repair times through guided maintenance procedures",
            "Increase in the customer experience"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Opportunity to enable new forms of human-to-machine interaction in production and\r\nmaintenance processes"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 38,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Augmented and Virtual Reality paradigm impact the prediction strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Opportunity to enable a safer and more controlled training environment for workers",
            "Increase in quality control",
            "Reduction in human error and downtime by increasing the availability of all relevant information in real time",
            "Increase in collaboration and learning on the field among more people remotely in production and maintenance processes"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in human error and downtime by increasing the availability of all relevant information in real time"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 39,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Internet of Things paradigm impact the centralization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Opportunity to enable the real-time location of materials and products along the supply chain",
            "Increase in work productivity by continuously monitoring working conditions",
            "Reduction in product repair time by signalling the need for maintenance before the product breaks",
            "Increase in the simplicity of use of the product by reducing human intervention"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Opportunity to enable the real-time location of materials and products along the supply chain"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 40,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Internet of Things paradigm impact the interoperability strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in work productivity by continuously monitoring working conditions",
            "Increase in the accuracy of the verification of the conditions of transport and storage of the products",
            "Increase in communication and interaction between intelligent products (through decision-making capabilities) and centralized controlling units",
            "Reduction in the role of intermediaries in the relationship with the customer"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in communication and interaction between intelligent products (through decision- making capabilities) and centralized controlling units"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 41,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Internet of Things paradigm impact the flexibility strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in work productivity by continuously monitoring working conditions",
            "Increase in the accuracy of the verification of the conditions of transport and storage of the products",
            "Reduction in unexpected failures and the amount of preventive maintenance for products",
            "Increase in the offer of personalized and automated services by leveraging IoT data"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the offer of personalized and automated services by leveraging IoT data"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 42,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Internet of Things paradigm impact the internalization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Opportunity to enable the real-time location of materials and products along the supply chain",
            "Increase in efficiency in supply chain management by continuously integrating more detailed information from the various partners in the supply chain",
            "Reduction in unexpected failures and the amount of preventive maintenance for products",
            "Reduction in the role of intermediaries in the relationship with the customer"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the role of intermediaries in the relationship with the customer"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 43,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Internet of Things paradigm impact the automation strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in work productivity by continuously monitoring working conditions",
            "Reduction in unexpected failures and the amount of preventive maintenance for machinery",
            "Reduction in the role of intermediaries in the relationship with the customer",
            "Opportunity to enable the real-time location of materials and products along the supply chain"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in unexpected failures and the amount of preventive maintenance for machinery"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 44,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Cloud Computing paradigm impact the security strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the cost for initial investments and subsequent maintenance of physical infrastructures and software applications",
            "Increase in the inviolability of physical infrastructures and software applications by centralizing cybersecurity procedures",
            "Increase in process monitoring and control",
            "Increase in data sharing between sites and organizational boundaries"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the inviolability of physical infrastructures and software applications by centralizing cybersecurity procedures"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 45,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Cloud Computing paradigm impact the efficiency strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the cost for the use of physical infrastructures making them infrastructure as-a-service (IaaS)",
            "Increase in the inviolability of physical infrastructures and software applications by centralizing cybersecurity procedures",
            "Possibility to enable the use of physical infrastructures and immediately scalable software applications",
            "Increase in data sharing between sites and organizational boundaries"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the cost for the use of physical infrastructures making them infrastructure as- a-service (IaaS)"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 46,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Cloud Computing paradigm impact the externalization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the risk of technological obsolescence of physical infrastructures and software applications",
            "Reduction in energy waste in the use of physical infrastructures by exploiting economies of scale",
            "Increase in the inviolability of physical infrastructures and software applications by centralizing cybersecurity procedures",
            "Possibility to enable the use of physical infrastructures and software applications at all times"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the risk of technological obsolescence of physical infrastructures and software applications"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 47,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Cloud Computing paradigm impact the centralization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the risk of technological obsolescence of physical infrastructures and software applications",
            "Possibility to enable the use of physical infrastructures and software applications everywhere",
            "Increase in process monitoring and control",
            "Increase in data sharing between sites and organizational boundaries"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in process monitoring and control"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 48,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Industrial Cloud Computing paradigm impact the simplification strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the cost for the use of software applications making them as-a-service (SaaS)",
            "Possibility to enable the use of physical infrastructures and software applications at all times",
            "Possibility to enable the use of physical infrastructures and immediately scalable software applications",
            "Increase in process monitoring and control"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in process monitoring and control"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 49,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Simulation paradigm impact the prediction strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in the information on the residual time of use or storage of component parts also to identify those that can be reused",
            "Increase in the iterations of designing new products and processes",
            "Reduction in the risks of incorrect design reflecting the requests of users in the realization of the product",
            "Reduction in the time and cost of reconfiguring machinery and systems by continuously adapting them to the dynamic production context"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the information on the residual time of use or storage of component parts also to identify those that can be reused"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 50,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Simulation paradigm impact the usability strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in the information on the residual time of use or storage of component parts also to identify those that can be reused",
            "Increase in the efficiency in the use of internal handling equipment by simulating the different assembly phases",
            "Reduction in the risks of incorrect design by preventing potential errors through the simulation of product behavior",
            "Opportunity to enable the design of advanced environmental management services"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the risks of incorrect design by preventing potential errors through the simulation of product behavior"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 51,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Simulation paradigm have an impact on the decentralization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the costs (economic and environmental) of procurement by foreseeing the costs in the choice of alternative suppliers",
            "Increase in the iterations of designing new products and processes",
            "Reduction in the risks of incorrect design reflecting the requests of users in the realization of the product",
            "Possibility to enable the design of advanced environmental management services"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Reduction in the costs (economic and environmental) of procurement by foreseeing the costs in the choice of alternative suppliers"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 52,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Simulation paradigm impact the externalization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in the information on the residual time of use or storage of component parts also to identify those that can be reused",
            "Increase in the possibility of collaboration at the supply chain level by simulating the overall process, forecasting economic, social and environmental performance",
            "Increase in the efficiency in the use of internal handling equipment by simulating the different assembly phases",
            "Reduction in the risks of incorrect design by preventing potential errors through the simulation of product behaviour"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the possibility of collaboration at the supply chain level by simulating the overall process, forecasting economic, social and environmental performance"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 53,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Simulation paradigm impact the flexibility strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in the costs (economic and environmental) of procurement by foreseeing the costs in the choice of alternative suppliers",
            "Increase in the information on the residual time of use or storage of component parts also to identify those that can be reused",
            "Increase in the iterations of designing new products and processes",
            "Increase in control by monitoring the correctness and efficiency of the production process"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the iterations of designing new products and processes"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 54,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Big Data Analytics (descriptive analytics) paradigm impacts the efficiency strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in quality of insight generation that help solve customer issues and increase customer experience",
            "Increase in quality in the search for purchasing commonalities to negotiate better pricing",
            "Increase in quality of the tracking of goods along the supply chain for demand planning",
            "Increase in quality of the tracking of product usage, performance, and positioning"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in quality in the search for purchasing commonalities to negotiate better pricing"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 55,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Big Data Analytics (predictive analytics) paradigm impacts the automation strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in the speed of adjusting the regular behaviour of machines with their expected behavior",
            "Increase in the ability of improving the user service experience",
            "Increase in the ability of differentiating and developing innovative products and services",
            "Increase in the ability of providing better services thanks to the identification of future customer behaviour"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the speed of adjusting the regular behaviour of machines with their expected behavior"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 56,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Big Data Analytics (predictive analytics) paradigm impacts the efficiency strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in the ability of improving the user service experience",
            "Increase in the ability of differentiating and developing innovative products and services",
            "Increase in the speed of activating quality control for the maintenance of machinery and products",
            "Increase in the capability of uncovering patterns, tracking movements, and analysing customer preferences to make more accurate market profiling and segmentation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the speed of activating quality control for the maintenance of machinery and products"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 57,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Big Data Analytics (prescriptive analytics) paradigm impacts the efficiency strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in rapidity in response to market demand",
            "Increase in real-time planning of energy consumption savings during breaks, reducing machine consumption",
            "Increase in the ability to modify routes of vehicles in real-time based on unforeseen events",
            "Increase in the capability to anticipate design flaws and correct them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in real-time planning of energy consumption savings during breaks, reducing machine consumption"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 58,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Structural Horizontal and Vertical System Integration paradigm impact the decentralization strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in information sharing with suppliers",
            "Reduction in production times by improving the use of machinery thanks to real-time planning",
            "Increase in decision-making support based on up-to-date production information and incoming orders",
            "Reduction in time-to-market"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in information sharing with suppliers"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 59,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Structural Horizontal and Vertical System Integration paradigm impact the interoperability strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in decision-making support based on up-to-date production information and incoming orders",
            "Reduction in delivery times by coordinating and adapting production and distribution processes",
            "Increase in customer relations by facilitating joint product design",
            "Increase in the flexible and dynamic interaction between partners in the production process"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the flexible and dynamic interaction between partners in the production process"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 60,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Structural Horizontal and Vertical System Integration paradigm impact the reactivity strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Reduction in time-to-market",
            "Increase in control over digital channels and smart products to improve the customer experience",
            "Increase in the traceability of data horizontally along the supply chain thanks to signalling systems",
            "Increase in customer relations by facilitating joint product design"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the traceability of data horizontally along the supply chain thanks to signalling systems"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 61,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Structural Horizontal and Vertical System Integration paradigm impact the flexibility strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in the capacity for self-organization and flexible reconfiguration of production lines for customized products",
            "Increase in the efficiency in the use of resources thanks to sharing between collaborative networks",
            "Reduction in production times by improving the use of machinery thanks to real-time planning",
            "Reduction in delivery times by coordinating and adapting production and distribution processes"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in the capacity for self-organization and flexible reconfiguration of production lines for customized products"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 62,
        "question": "Which of the following \u201cOperational Benefits\u201d of the Structural Horizontal and Vertical System Integration paradigm impact the complexification strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increase in customer relations by facilitating joint product design",
            "Increase in interaction between products to perform complex cooperation tasks",
            "Reduction in time-to-market",
            "Reduction in production times by improving the use of machinery thanks to real-time planning"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increase in interaction between products to perform complex cooperation tasks"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 63,
        "question": "Building an agile and hybrid organization may represent a valid solution:",
        "answers": [
            "to design and build sound software tools",
            "to survive and thrive through digital disruption",
            "to encompass more digital processes",
            "to nourish the organization\u2019s competitive advantage"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "to survive and thrive through digital disruption"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 64,
        "question": "The connection between business models and technology:",
        "answers": [
            "Both need to be coherent",
            "technology influences business models and business models necessitate the use of technologies",
            "business models influence the chosen technology",
            "technology influences business models and technologies necessitate business models"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "technology influences business models and technologies necessitate business models"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 65,
        "question": "Technological advancements:",
        "answers": [
            "Have proper economic value",
            "Have no economic value",
            "Have an economic value, which is challenging to measure",
            "Have an economic value if they are properly implemented within business models"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Have an economic value if they are properly implemented within business models"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 66,
        "question": "A business model which is driven by the Industry 4.0 digital paradigms:",
        "answers": [
            "will use technologies as an input in order to extract value and generate a valuable output for its customer base",
            "will use technologies as an input to speed up production and become more efficient",
            "will use technologies to innovate all its building blocks",
            "will use technologies to create new products and services."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "will use technologies as an input in order to extract value and generate a valuable output for its customer base"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 67,
        "question": "Data-driven business models are typically adopted by organizations operating:",
        "answers": [
            "B2B",
            "B2C",
            "C2B",
            "Can be implemented by any business and or consumer models"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C2B"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 68,
        "question": "Customer-to-Business (C2B) sector means:",
        "answers": [
            "markets within which innovative products are designed and developed from the data generated and collected as a result of product utilization as well as product-user interactions",
            "markets within which innovative products are gathered directly from customers",
            "markets within which customers create and deliver innovative products with the support of the organizations",
            "markets in which innovative products are the results of a multistakeholder active participation and cooperation."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "markets within which innovative products are designed and developed from the data generated and collected as a result of product utilization as well as product-user interactions"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 69,
        "question": "Platform business models are typically adopted by organizations operating:",
        "answers": [
            "B2B",
            "C2B",
            "C2C",
            "Can be implemented by any business and or consumer models"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C2C"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 70,
        "question": "Smart factory business models are typically adopted by organizations operating:",
        "answers": [
            "B2B",
            "C2B",
            "C2C",
            "Can be implemented by any business and or consumer models"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B2B"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 71,
        "question": "Servitization business models are typically adopted by organizations operating:",
        "answers": [
            "B2B",
            "C2B",
            "B2C",
            "Can be implemented by any business and or consumer models"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B2C"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 72,
        "question": "Smart factory business models are associated with the strategic dimension of:",
        "answers": [
            "Operational excellence",
            "Product leadership",
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Ecosystem leadership"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Operational excellence"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 73,
        "question": "Servitization business models are associated with the strategic dimension of:",
        "answers": [
            "Operational excellence",
            "Product leadership",
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Ecosystem leadership"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Product leadership"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 74,
        "question": "Data driven business models are associated with the strategic dimension of:",
        "answers": [
            "Operational excellence",
            "Product leadership",
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Ecosystem leadership"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Customer intimacy"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 75,
        "question": "Platform business models are associated with the strategic dimension of:",
        "answers": [
            "Operational excellence",
            "Product leadership",
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Ecosystem leadership"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Ecosystem leadership"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 76,
        "question": "Datafication means:",
        "answers": [
            "generation and collection of data and the extraction of valuable knowledge",
            "data analysis and the extraction of valuable knowledge",
            "big data analytics the extraction of valuable knowledge",
            "data measurement and the extraction of valuable knowledge"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "generation and collection of data and the extraction of valuable knowledge"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 77,
        "question": "Organizations achieve economies of scale through:",
        "answers": [
            "a wider variety of goods and services",
            "production level increments",
            "price increase",
            "production efficiency measures"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "production level increments"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 78,
        "question": "Organizations achieve economies of scope and complementarities through:",
        "answers": [
            "a wider variety of goods and services",
            "production level increments",
            "price increase",
            "production efficiency measures"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "a wider variety of goods and services"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 79,
        "question": "Operating models refer to the abstract and visual representation of the modalities through which organizations:",
        "answers": [
            "understand the best marketing ways to enter new business segments",
            "structure their core processes and deliver value to their customers",
            "structure their core processes to increase their efficacy and effectiveness",
            "structure their core processes to reduce the costs of the operations"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "structure their core processes and deliver value to their customers"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 80,
        "question": "Operating models:",
        "answers": [
            "are standardized",
            "although they can be employed by any organization, are particularly relevant for large corporations",
            "can range from simple to complex",
            "should follow some best practices."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "can range from simple to complex"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 81,
        "question": "Digital scale, scope and learning:",
        "answers": [
            "are able to reshape the nature of competitive advantage",
            "do not affect company dimension",
            "can represent a challenge that organizations need to address",
            "represent a doubtful advantage"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "are able to reshape the nature of competitive advantage"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 82,
        "question": "Monetization means:",
        "answers": [
            "generating value from a particular product or service",
            "generating data from a particular product or service",
            "generating competitive advantage from a particular product or service",
            "generating money from a particular product or service"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "generating money from a particular product or service"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 83,
        "question": "In digital companies:",
        "answers": [
            "The marginal cost of serving an additional user on multiple digital networks is higher than that of non-digital companies",
            "The marginal cost of serving an additional user on multiple digital networks is limited",
            "The marginal cost of serving an additional user on multiple digital networks is close to zero",
            "The marginal cost of serving an additional user on multiple digital networks cannot be overlooked"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The marginal cost of serving an additional user on multiple digital networks is close to zero"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 84,
        "question": "In digital companies, learning and innovation are:",
        "answers": [
            "Faster",
            "More efficient",
            "More challenging",
            "Not relevant"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Faster"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 85,
        "question": "Digital operating models:",
        "answers": [
            "Must be aligned with digital business model to optimize performance",
            "Can enable faster learning and innovation",
            "Are able to transform industries and reshape competitive advantage",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 86,
        "question": "Digital operating models are based on:",
        "answers": [
            "Data monetization",
            "Software development",
            "Customer intimacy",
            "Data generation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Software development"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 87,
        "question": "Product dematerialization refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "cyber services available to users",
            "data available to users",
            "cyber goods available to users",
            "tangible goods available to users"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "cyber goods available to users"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 88,
        "question": "A bug is:",
        "answers": [
            "a fault causing a program to crash or to produce invalid output",
            "a cyber attack which should be followed by cyber resilience activities",
            "a cyber attack which should be followed by cyber security activities",
            "a technical issue of the system"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "a fault causing a program to crash or to produce invalid output"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 89,
        "question": "ETL stands for:",
        "answers": [
            "extraction, transformation and logging",
            "extraction, translation and loading",
            "extraction, translation and logging",
            "extraction, transformation and loading"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "extraction, transformation and loading"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 90,
        "question": "In the process of resolving bugs within software or computer programs, \u201copen data\u201d is part of the:",
        "answers": [
            "Society building block",
            "Internal processes building block",
            "Resources building block",
            "External processes building block"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Society building block"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 91,
        "question": "In a randomized control trial, the treatment refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "Random users who experience the innovation",
            "Random users who keep using the original system",
            "Selected users who experience the innovation",
            "Selected users who keep using the original system"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Random users who experience the innovation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 92,
        "question": "In a randomized control trial, the control refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "Random users who experience the innovation",
            "Random users who keep using the original system",
            "Selected users who experience the innovation",
            "Selected users who keep using the original system"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Random users who keep using the original system"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 93,
        "question": "The expression \u201cendless users anywhere and anytime\u201d means that",
        "answers": [
            "the cost per unit of output decreases as the scale of production increases",
            "the cost per unit of input decreases as the scale of production decreases",
            "the cost per unit of output decreases as the scale of production decreases",
            "the cost per unit of input decreases as the scale of production increases"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "the cost per unit of output decreases as the scale of production increases"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 94,
        "question": "The term \u201cartificial intelligence\u201d was coined by John McCarthy in:",
        "answers": [
            "1946",
            "1956",
            "1966",
            "1976"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "1956"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 95,
        "question": "According to modern artificial intelligence approach:",
        "answers": [
            "machines have to be equipped with rules of logical reasoning",
            "machines have to be equipped with real world conditions",
            "machines exhibit  intelligence, as characterized by sufficient computational resources and algorithms defining a learning process",
            "its effectiveness relies thoroughly on the clarity of rules and definitions"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "machines exhibit intelligence, as characterized by sufficient computational resources and"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 96,
        "question": "In innovative digital operating models, the concept of \u201cendless users anywhere and anytime\u201d refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "the internal processes building block",
            "the resources building block",
            "the value proposition building block",
            "the external processes building block"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "the value proposition building block"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 97,
        "question": "A digital-first product is:",
        "answers": [
            "a good which functions are controlled by software",
            "a service which functions are controlled by software",
            "a software tool",
            "a good characterized by high tech components"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "a good which functions are controlled by software"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 98,
        "question": "The personal level in the development of digital-first goods or services refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "The issues brought by technologies to individuals\u2019 lives",
            "The ethical boundaries brought by technologies to individuals\u2019 lives",
            "The challenges brought by technologies to individuals\u2019 lives",
            "The benefits brought by technologies to individuals\u2019 lives"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The benefits brought by technologies to individuals\u2019 lives"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 99,
        "question": "The social level in the development of digital-first goods or services refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "the challenges of technological innovation on society and on social relationships",
            "the impacts of technological innovation on society and on social relationships",
            "the opportunities of technological innovation on society and on social relationships",
            "the ethical boundaries of technological innovation on society and on social relationships"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "the impacts of technological innovation on society and on social relationships"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 100,
        "question": "The business level in the development of digital-first goods or services refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "the opportunities of technological change within the industrial sphere",
            "the ethical boundaries of technological change within the industrial sphere",
            "the consequences of technological change within the industrial sphere",
            "the challenges of technological change within the industrial sphere"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "the consequences of technological change within the industrial sphere"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 101,
        "question": "The planet level in the development of digital-first goods or services refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "the environmental implications of technologies on the planet",
            "the environmental use of resources to enhance technologies",
            "the amount of spared resources",
            "the impact of technologies on forests"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "the environmental implications of technologies on the planet"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 102,
        "question": "The fact that digital goods have the ability to predict the future and to proactively react to complex problems can lead to:",
        "answers": [
            "Predictive maintenance",
            "Big data analytics",
            "Customer engagement",
            "Data optimization"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Predictive maintenance"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 103,
        "question": "The digital products\u2019 ability to provide users with personalized recommendations can enhance:",
        "answers": [
            "Customer experience",
            "Customer loyalty",
            "Data optimization",
            "Cyber security"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Customer experience"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 104,
        "question": "Digital first products can:",
        "answers": [
            "Be constantly upgraded, as well as traditional products",
            "Interact with further systems and traditional products",
            "Learn, adjust and continually evolve thanks to artificial intelligence",
            "Not be constantly upgraded according to the customers\u2019 feedback"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Learn, adjust and continually evolve thanks to artificial intelligence"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 105,
        "question": "Sensors:",
        "answers": [
            "Allow collecting data autonomously",
            "Doesn\u2019t need to be incorporated into the product",
            "Are useful only if the product can be defined as \u201caugmented\u201d",
            "Should follow strict cyber security paradigms"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Allow collecting data autonomously"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 106,
        "question": "Connecting more digital products can lead to:",
        "answers": [
            "Enhanced computational power",
            "Enhanced data availability",
            "Enhanced efficiency in feedback",
            "Enhanced cyber security"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Enhanced data availability"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 107,
        "question": "Artificial intelligence:",
        "answers": [
            "Can organize data and identify patterns to enhance and formulate predictions",
            "Cannot be applied in decision-making",
            "Can substitute human judgement in the decision-making within organizations",
            "Is essential to navigate and untangle decision-making process within organizations"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Can organize data and identify patterns to enhance and formulate predictions"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 108,
        "question": "The business model building block which is less impacted by data-driven business models is:",
        "answers": [
            "resources",
            "customers,",
            "internal processes",
            "society"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Society"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 109,
        "question": "Which of the following does not refer to customer intimacy?",
        "answers": [
            "Increased product range and customization",
            "complementary goods",
            "data testing",
            "customer engagement"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Data testing"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 110,
        "question": "In data-driven business models, the volume of data available is:",
        "answers": [
            "Essential",
            "Very important, still not sufficient",
            "Not relevant",
            "Given for granted"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Very important, still not sufficient"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 111,
        "question": "In data-driven business models, data generation activities:",
        "answers": [
            "Have the aim of collecting large amount of data",
            "Have the aim of generating structured organizational data",
            "Are part of the value proposition",
            "Require sound cyber security systems"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Have the aim of generating structured organizational data"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 112,
        "question": "Data integration:",
        "answers": [
            "Stands as an essential activity to translate data into information",
            "Requires the use of large amount of data",
            "Can be done by adding data from external sources",
            "Is a relevant task of the resource building block"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Stands as an essential activity to translate data into information"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 113,
        "question": "Data analysis:",
        "answers": [
            "Stands as an essential activity to translate data into knowledge and skills",
            "Requires the use of large amount of data",
            "Can be done by integrating data from external sources",
            "Is a relevant task of the resource building block"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Stands as an essential activity to translate data into knowledge and skills"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 114,
        "question": "Customer profiling can lead to:",
        "answers": [
            "Additional data",
            "New market spaces",
            "Operational excellence",
            "Product upgrading"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "New market spaces"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 115,
        "question": "Product co-design can lead to:",
        "answers": [
            "Additional data",
            "New product development",
            "Operational excellence",
            "New market niches"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "New product development"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 116,
        "question": "The post-sale process:",
        "answers": [
            "Is characterized by the acquisition of augmented products and services",
            "Is characterized by the utilization of augmented products and services",
            "Is a critical stage of the customer journey",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 117,
        "question": "The Consumer-to-Business (C2B) sales models happens when:",
        "answers": [
            "Customers sell back the product to the company",
            "Customers resell the product to other customers",
            "Consumers contribute to generating value",
            "Consumers contribute to data collection and analysis"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Consumers contribute to generating value"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 118,
        "question": "Indirect data monetization refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of duplicating data",
            "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of extracting value",
            "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of increasing effectiveness",
            "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of customer intimacy"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of extracting value"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 119,
        "question": "Human capital in indirect data monetization:",
        "answers": [
            "Is essential in order to convert data into knowledge",
            "Can benefit from the new business models",
            "See a change in their role",
            "Are less involved in the process"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Is essential in order to convert data into knowledge"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 120,
        "question": "In indirect data monetization, internal data:",
        "answers": [
            "Derive from online user interactions",
            "Represent a rare asset to imitate",
            "Derive from organizational processes and public sources",
            "Are impossible to be acquired from other sources"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Are impossible to be acquired from other sources"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 121,
        "question": "In the data-drive business model, \u201cpositive consumer experience\u201d belongs to:",
        "answers": [
            "The society business model canvas building block",
            "The customer business model canvas building block",
            "The product business model canvas building block",
            "The value proposition business model canvas building block"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The value proposition business model canvas building block"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 122,
        "question": "Product up-selling means:",
        "answers": [
            "creating an automatic upgrade of the products",
            "designing and selling an enhanced version of a determined product or service",
            "collecting high-end data",
            "customizing the product according to the users\u2019 wishes"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "designing and selling an enhanced version of a determined product or service"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 123,
        "question": "Product upgrading means:",
        "answers": [
            "collecting high-end data",
            "customizing the product according to the users\u2019 wishes",
            "creating an automatic upgrade of the products",
            "utilizing insights from product-users interactions in order to upgrade the products"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "utilizing insights from product-users interactions in order to upgrade the products"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 124,
        "question": "In the data-drive business model, \u201cadditional product features\u201d belong to:",
        "answers": [
            "The society business model canvas building block",
            "The customer business model canvas building block",
            "The product business model canvas building block",
            "The value proposition business model canvas building block"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The product business model canvas building block"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 125,
        "question": "New product development means:",
        "answers": [
            "creating an automatic upgrade of the products",
            "designing and selling an enhanced version of a determined product or service",
            "distributing a new product or service to the market",
            "customizing the product according to the users\u2019 wishes"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "distributing a new product or service to the market"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 126,
        "question": "Product cross-selling means:",
        "answers": [
            "distributing related or complementary digital-first goods or services",
            "creating an automatic upgrade of the products",
            "designing and selling an enhanced version of a determined product or service",
            "distributing a new product or service to the market"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "distributing related or complementary digital-first goods or services"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 127,
        "question": "Direct data monetization refers to:",
        "answers": [
            "the process of granting a third-party access to organizational data in order to generate a direct revenue stream",
            "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of extracting value",
            "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of increasing effectiveness",
            "the process of analyzing and processing data available within the company for the purpose of customer intimacy"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "the process of granting a third-party access to organizational data in order to generate a direct revenue stream"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 128,
        "question": "The business model building block which is less impacted by platform business models is:",
        "answers": [
            "resources",
            "customers,",
            "internal processes",
            "society"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "internal processes"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 129,
        "question": "Digital technologies in platform business models allow:",
        "answers": [
            "effective and efficient interactions between producers and consumers",
            "enhanced data collection from customers",
            "product availability",
            "operational excellence"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "effective and efficient interactions between producers and consumers"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 130,
        "question": "Ecosystem leadership happens when:",
        "answers": [
            "high quality data are collected",
            "customer needs are fulfilled through the purchase of shared products",
            "customer needs are fulfilled through the purchase of personalized products",
            "customer intimacy increases"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "customer needs are fulfilled through the purchase of shared products"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 131,
        "question": "Which of the following elements do not pertain to platform business models:",
        "answers": [
            "digitization of consumer behavior",
            "digitization of selling processes",
            "digitization of identity and trust",
            "digitization of location"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "digitization of selling processes"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 132,
        "question": "Which of the following elements does not pertain to platform-based business models:",
        "answers": [
            "connectivity",
            "safety",
            "openness",
            "scalability"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "safety"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 133,
        "question": "Business ecosystems represent:",
        "answers": [
            "specific industrial sectors involved in the delivery of particular products or services through both competition and cooperation",
            "industrial districts involved in the delivery of particular products or services through both competition and cooperation",
            "a network of professional operators involved in the delivery of particular products or services through both competition and cooperation",
            "a network of companies, individuals, and organizations, involved in the delivery of particular products or services through both competition and cooperation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "a network of companies, individuals, and organizations, involved in the delivery of particular products or services through both competition and cooperation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 134,
        "question": "By the term \"coring\" we mean:",
        "answers": [
            "a set of activities to identify or design technologies and products and to render them fundamental to a market",
            "a set of strategic activities which companies execute to emerge as dominant players within the market",
            "a set of activities which are carried on to collect high quality data",
            "a set of strategic activities which are carried on to increase customer intimacy"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "a set of activities to identify or design technologies and products and to render them fundamental to a market"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 135,
        "question": "By the term \"tipping\" we mean:",
        "answers": [
            "a set of activities to identify or design technologies and products and to render them fundamental to a market",
            "a set of strategic activities which companies execute to emerge as dominant players within the market",
            "a set of activities which are carried on to collect high quality data",
            "a set of strategic activities which are carried on to increase customer intimacy"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "a set of strategic activities which companies execute to emerge as dominant players within the market"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 136,
        "question": "Network effects contribute to",
        "answers": [
            "enhancing value creation",
            "enhancing customer intimacy",
            "enhancing high value data collection",
            "empowering the co-design of new or upgraded products"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "enhancing value creation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 137,
        "question": "Network effects can be:",
        "answers": [
            "positive",
            "negative",
            "both positive and negative",
            "dependent on the quality of collected data"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "both positive and negative"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 138,
        "question": "Which of the following does not represent a shift brought forth by platform-based business models:",
        "answers": [
            "Shift in markets",
            "Shift in competitive advantage",
            "Shift in data collection",
            "Shift in value creation"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Shift in data collection"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 139,
        "question": "In platform-based business models:",
        "answers": [
            "Participants allows producers and consumers to meet",
            "Participants can be either producers or consumers",
            "Users are represented by both producers as well as consumers",
            "Participants act as producers as well as consumers"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Users are represented by both producers as well as consumers"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 140,
        "question": "In platform-base business models, high value interactions are not built through:",
        "answers": [
            "attracting attention",
            "collecting and sharing high-quality data",
            "building a reputation",
            "enabling monetization"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "collecting and sharing high-quality data"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 141,
        "question": "G Suite is an example of",
        "answers": [
            "Product dematerialization",
            "Data-driven business model",
            "Platform business model",
            "Tangible product"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Product dematerialization"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 142,
        "question": "Facebook is an example of",
        "answers": [
            "Platform business model",
            "Data-driven business model",
            "Direct data monetization",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 143,
        "question": "Maintain user interests in a platform means:",
        "answers": [
            "encouraging participants to use the service",
            "increasing the number of passive participants",
            "increasing the number of prosumer participants",
            "increasing the total number of participants"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "encouraging participants to use the service"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 144,
        "question": "In order to build and maintain a good reputation, platform businesses:",
        "answers": [
            "Must adopt data security measures",
            "Must implement a clear privacy and data management policy",
            "Must verify the identity of participants within the ecosystem",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 145,
        "question": "In order to monetize the business without inhibiting the continuous growth of the network effect, platform companies should:",
        "answers": [
            "Charge for the value the platform creates for users",
            "Charge for users access",
            "Charge for users utilization of the platform",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Charge for the value the platform creates for users"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 146,
        "question": "By Network-Marketplace-Community Layer, we mean:",
        "answers": [
            "Value creation within the participants",
            "High-quality data collection within the network",
            "Digital infrastructure for value creation",
            "Cyber resilience within the network"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Value creation within the participants"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 147,
        "question": "By Infrastructure Layer, we mean:",
        "answers": [
            "Value creation within the participants",
            "High-quality data collection within the network",
            "Digital infrastructure for value creation",
            "Cyber resilience within the network"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Digital infrastructure for value creation"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 148,
        "question": "By Data Layer, we mean:",
        "answers": [
            "Value creation within the participants",
            "High-quality data collection within the network",
            "Digital infrastructure for value creation",
            "Cyber resilience within the network"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "High-quality data collection within the network"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 149,
        "question": "What is the principal asset which characterized digital ecosystems?",
        "answers": [
            "Internet connection",
            "Technological advancements",
            "Data",
            "Artificial intelligence"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Data"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 150,
        "question": "What kind of business model introduces the concept of prosumer?",
        "answers": [
            "Smart factory business model",
            "Servitization business model",
            "Data confederation business model",
            "Data-driven business model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Data confederation business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 151,
        "question": "The mass production of high customized products is called:",
        "answers": [
            "Personalization",
            "Mass customization",
            "Mass personalization",
            "Customization"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Mass customization"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 152,
        "question": "The connection between platform-based businesses and their users can be described as:",
        "answers": [
            "Users contribute data providing relevant information to improve user experience",
            "Platforms contribute data providing relevant information to improve user experience",
            "Users contribute money to improve the platform business model",
            "Platforms sell their product to users, improving user experience"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Users contribute data providing relevant information to improve user experience"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 153,
        "question": "What company represents an example of data confederation business model?",
        "answers": [
            "Facebook",
            "Amazon go.",
            "Aircraft",
            "TripAdvisor"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "TripAdvisor"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 154,
        "question": "The platform social network business model, like Facebook, monetizes through:",
        "answers": [
            "Users\u2019 fees",
            "Advertisers\u2019 posts",
            "User\u2019s data",
            "Both advertisers\u2019 posts and users data"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Both advertisers\u2019 posts and users data"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 155,
        "question": "What are the forms of exchange in the platform businesses:",
        "answers": [
            "Information and currency",
            "Good/services",
            "Currency and good/services",
            "Information, good/services, and social currency"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Information, good/services, and social currency"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 156,
        "question": "Airbnb is an example of:",
        "answers": [
            "Marketplace platform business model",
            "Data-confederation business model",
            "Social-network business model",
            "Phygital operating model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Marketplace platform business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 157,
        "question": "Which devices are not physical components of a cyber-physical system?",
        "answers": [
            "Processors",
            "Sensors",
            "Memory",
            "Display"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Display"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 158,
        "question": "A digital twin:",
        "answers": [
            "Consists of physical representation serving as the real-time counterpart of a physical object or process.",
            "Consist of virtual representation serving as the real-time digital counterpart of a physical object or process",
            "Consist of virtual representation serving as the real-time digital counterpart of another virtual object or process",
            "Consist of physical representation serving as the real-time physical counterpart of a virtual object or process"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Consists of a virtual representation serving as the real-time digital counterpart of a physical object or process."
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 159,
        "question": "Digital twins:",
        "answers": [
            "enable communication along the supply chain and allow organizations to build collaborative business networks",
            "compare real and expected performances to develop predictive maintenance",
            "simulate the behaviour of the physical device in order to prevent errors and support its implementation",
            "all the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "all the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 160,
        "question": "Which feature doesn\u2019t describe production enabled by cyber-physical production system?",
        "answers": [
            "Flexible",
            "Transparent",
            "Decentralized",
            "Automated"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Transparent"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 161,
        "question": "Which technology of the following ones isn\u2019t going to support the phygital operating model?",
        "answers": [
            "Blockchain",
            "Artificial intelligence",
            "Internet of things",
            "5G"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "blockchain"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 162,
        "question": "The implementation of smart factory business model give us the possibility of:",
        "answers": [
            "Optimizing resource utilization",
            "Reducing the inventory",
            "Increasing time-to-market",
            "Increasing lead-time"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Optimizing resource utilization"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 163,
        "question": "What of the following is not a smart factory characteristic:",
        "answers": [
            "Proactiveness",
            "Intelligence",
            "Connectedness",
            "Transparency"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Intelligence"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 164,
        "question": "What of the following is not a cyber-physical product characteristic:",
        "answers": [
            "Awareness",
            "Intelligence",
            "Connectedness",
            "Transparency"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Transparency"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 165,
        "question": "The smart factory business model:",
        "answers": [
            "Increases product price",
            "Increases end-product quality",
            "Increases necessity of employees",
            "Increases organizational procedures complexity"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Increases end-product quality"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 166,
        "question": "M2M communication means:",
        "answers": [
            "Man-to-machine communication.",
            "Machine-to-machine communication",
            "Machine-to-Man communication",
            "Man-to-Man communication"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Machine-to-machine communication"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 167,
        "question": "In industry 4.0, to establish future organizational competitiveness, manufacturers should shift:",
        "answers": [
            "From Interconnected supply chain to digital linear supply chain",
            "From linear supply chain to a digital supply network",
            "From interconnected supply chain to a digital supply network",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "From linear supply chain to a digital supply network"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 168,
        "question": "Agility is referred to the organizational ability:",
        "answers": [
            "To thrive in a competitive environment of continuous and unanticipated change",
            "To reduce the manufacturing lead time",
            "To create rigid and stable collaboration structures",
            "To deliver consumer customized solutions"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "To thrive in a competitive environment of continuous and unanticipated change"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 169,
        "question": "Hub and spoke business models accomplish:",
        "answers": [
            "Decentralization",
            "Centralization",
            "Externalization",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Centralization"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 170,
        "question": "Servitization business models reduce the gap between:",
        "answers": [
            "Physical and digital manufacturing",
            "Externalization and control",
            "Manufacturing products and providing services",
            "Collecting data and extracting information"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Manufacturing products and providing services (CECI)"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 171,
        "question": "What are the major drivers of Servitization business model?",
        "answers": [
            "Building durable customer relationship and reduce the production costs",
            "Building a durable customers relationship, reducing environmental costs, extending existing services and optimizing asset utilization",
            "Reducing environmental impact through circular economy.",
            "Increasing efficiency through automation and machine learning."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Building a durable customers relationship, reducing environmental costs, extending existing\r\nservices and optimizing asset utilization"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 172,
        "question": "What is the meaning of the Servitization paradox?",
        "answers": [
            "Difficulty to create incremental profits through services as a consequence of increased costs",
            "Difficulty to create incremental profits through services as a consequence of reduced prices",
            "Possibility to create incremental profits through services as a consequence of reduced costs.",
            "Possibility to create incremental profits through services as a consequence of increased prices."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Difficulty to create incremental profits through services as a consequence of increased\r\ncosts"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 173,
        "question": "What is the so-called service expansion double effect as a part of the Servitization business model?",
        "answers": [
            "Additional revenues and gain consumer loyalty",
            "Additional revenues and lower costs",
            "Additional revenues and lower investments",
            "The same revenues and lower costs"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Additional revenues and gain consumer loyalty"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 174,
        "question": "What is the meaning of product cannibalization of digital services?",
        "answers": [
            "The digital service integrate the good sale",
            "The digital service substitute the good sale",
            "The good sale substitute the digital service",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The digital service substitute the good sale"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 175,
        "question": "Which activity is not a core part of the value chain in a servitized enterprise?",
        "answers": [
            "Value offering monitoring",
            "Problem identification",
            "Value offering development",
            "Customer identification"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Customer identification"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 176,
        "question": "What is the definition of product availability business model?",
        "answers": [
            "Service providers own the product throughout its entire life cycle and transfer the good to consumers as a service",
            "Users possess the availability of a determined digital good or service rather than the ownership of the product",
            "A service solution is designed to be utilized in conjunction with the related dematerialized good",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Users possess the availability of a determined digital good or service rather than the\r\nownership of the product"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 177,
        "question": "What is the definition of product+service (add-on software) business model?",
        "answers": [
            "Service providers own the product throughout its entire life cycle and transfer the good to consumers as a service",
            "Users possess the availability of a determined digital good or service rather than the ownership of the product",
            "A service solution is designed to be utilized in conjunction with the related dematerialized good",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A service solution is designed to be utilized in conjunction with the related dematerialized\r\ngood"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 178,
        "question": "What is the definition of product-as-a-service business model?",
        "answers": [
            "Service providers own the product throughout its entire life cycle and transfer the good to consumers as a service",
            "Users possess the availability of a determined digital good or service rather than the ownership of the product",
            "A service solution is designed to be utilized in conjunction with the related dematerialized good",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Service providers own the product throughout its entire life cycle and transfer the good to\r\nconsumers as a service"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 179,
        "question": "Disney+ is a clear example of:",
        "answers": [
            "Product as a service",
            "Product subscription",
            "Product +service",
            "Product ownership"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Product subscription"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 180,
        "question": "Amazon Web Services represents an example of:",
        "answers": [
            "Hub and spoke business model",
            "Product as a service business model",
            "Product ownership business model",
            "Product +service business model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Product as a service business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 181,
        "question": "What is the Servitization business model pricing strategy?",
        "answers": [
            "Cost-plus pricing",
            "Value-based pricing",
            "Mark-up pricing",
            "Flexible pricing"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Value-based pricing"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 182,
        "question": "Ford Motor Company represents an example of:",
        "answers": [
            "Hub and spoke business model",
            "Product as a service business model",
            "Product ownership business model",
            "Product +service business model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Product ownership business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 183,
        "question": "In a smart factory, the ability to anticipate potential issues and challenges rather than reacting once complexities have occurred can be defined as:",
        "answers": [
            "Optimization",
            "Transparency",
            "Proactiveness",
            "Agility"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Proactiveness"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 184,
        "question": "In a smart factory, the possibility of an organization to view real-time notifications and alerts formulating accurate decisions is enabled by:",
        "answers": [
            "Transparency",
            "Optimization",
            "Connectedness",
            "Agility"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Transparency"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 185,
        "question": "In a smart factory, the possibility to execute operations with minimal manual intervention as well as human interaction through automation and synchronization is related to:",
        "answers": [
            "Transparency",
            "Connectedness",
            "Optimization",
            "Agility"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Optimization"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 186,
        "question": "The smart factory business model:",
        "answers": [
            "Use totally virtual systems",
            "Use totally physical systems",
            "Use both physical and virtual systems",
            "Use only online systems"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Use both physical and virtual systems"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 187,
        "question": "Amazon Go is a clear example of:",
        "answers": [
            "Servitization business model",
            "Phygital Operating model",
            "Platform business model",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Phygital Operating model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 188,
        "question": "Data confederation business model allows to:",
        "answers": [
            "Obtaining scope economies",
            "Obtain learning economies",
            "Increase customer loyalty",
            "All the options are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the options are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 189,
        "question": "Co-design is defined as :",
        "answers": [
            "The opportunity for customers to collaborate during the design process",
            "The production using physical and digital features",
            "The creation of a product from two collaborative companies",
            "The creation of a product using a circular economy system"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The opportunity for customers to collaborate during the design process"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 190,
        "question": "Big data analytics are used in the smart factory business model in the:",
        "answers": [
            "Design phase",
            "Production phase",
            "Monitoring phase",
            "Along all the supply chain"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Along all the supply chain"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 191,
        "question": "In digital manufacturing:",
        "answers": [
            "The distance separating the design of an object from its sale is melted",
            "You don\u2019t have to worry about designing of the production plant",
            "Creating the digital model of the object is not sufficient",
            "Is all about 3D printing"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "You don\u2019t have to worry about designing of the production plant"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 192,
        "question": "Collaborative robots:",
        "answers": [
            "Are generally programmed to perform a repetitive operation",
            "Don\u2019t have sensor mediated management",
            "Make a combined use of sensors and artificial intelligence to perform repetitive tasks",
            "Are able to think and act independently from the operator"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Are able to think and act independently from the operator"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 193,
        "question": "Virtual reality:",
        "answers": [
            "Enhances or add computer-based elements to the real world",
            "Isolates from the real world by creating a completely virtual one",
            "Can be marker-based, marker-less, projection-based or superimposition-based",
            "Brings digital components into a person\u2019s perception of the real world"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Isolates from the real world by creating a completely virtual one"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 194,
        "question": "In Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT):",
        "answers": [
            "Sensors can be connected only to the machines:",
            "Data are processed at the edge of the system, without the need for a cloud server",
            "Information and communication technologies are integrated within the delivering system",
            "Different devices are connected in order to communicate with each other as well as with a centralized unit of control"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Different devices are connected in order to communicate with each other as well as with a centralized unit of control"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 195,
        "question": "Cloud computing:",
        "answers": [
            "Allows the use of online resources, like storage and computing",
            "Is a decentralised hub that allows to process organizational data",
            "Is constituted by two essential elements, a front end and a back end",
            "Is not a major benefit of exploiting an online infrastructure"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Allows the use of online resources, like storage and computing"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 196,
        "question": "Simulations:",
        "answers": [
            "Make possible to evaluate results of different scenarios and choose the optimal one",
            "Are used to make virtual copies of physical objects",
            "Are used to simulate a set of activities by changing its variables and understand the impact of changes",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 197,
        "question": "In big data analytics:",
        "answers": [
            "Data-driven decision processes are structured mainly into two stages, data collection and processing",
            "The data-drive decision process uses data as an input and information insights as an output",
            "Companies has the opportunity to make decision-making process more subjective",
            "There are four main analytical capabilities, which are descriptive, diagnostic, predictive and active"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "The data-drive decision process uses data as an input and information insights as an output"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 198,
        "question": "Cybersecurity:",
        "answers": [
            "Should firstly protect data and make the security system resilient",
            "Guarantees protection of potential damage to hardware and software components",
            "Guarantees protection from data breaches",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 199,
        "question": "Structural horizontal integration:",
        "answers": [
            "Can\u2019t converge with vertical integration",
            "Refers to the coordinated management of the production chain",
            "Consists of the coordinated management of the product life cycle",
            "None of the answers is correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Refers to the coordinated management of the production chain"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 200,
        "question": "Vertical integration:",
        "answers": [
            "Can\u2019t converge with vertical integration",
            "Refers to the coordinated management of the production chain",
            "Consists of the coordinated management of the product life cycle",
            "None of the answers is correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Consists of the coordinated management of the product life cycle"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 201,
        "question": "Amazon success:",
        "answers": [
            "Is not due to its founder\u2019s strength and vision",
            "Is associated with one specific strategic innovation",
            "Is based on competitive positioning",
            "Is based on competitive movement"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Is based on competitive movement"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 202,
        "question": "Which of the four business models characterizing Industry 4.0 is involved in Amazon\u2019s value proposition?",
        "answers": [
            "Platform",
            "Data-driven",
            "Servitization",
            "All of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All of them"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 203,
        "question": "Which of the following tensions is Amazon able to exploit?",
        "answers": [
            "Knowledge exploration vs knowledge expansion",
            "Tradition vs innovation",
            "Artisan production vs industrial production",
            "Data vs algorithms"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Artisan production vs industrial production"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 204,
        "question": "Which of the following tensions is Amazon able to exploit?",
        "answers": [
            "Knowledge exploration vs knowledge expansion",
            "Profit vs sustainability",
            "Tradition vs innovation",
            "Data vs algorithms"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Profit vs sustainability"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 205,
        "question": "What does it mean that Amazon is an \u201calgorithmic business\u201d?",
        "answers": [
            "It is powered by data and algorithms and it learns from its mistakes and experiments",
            "It is powered by blockchain, but it doesn\u2019t learn form experiments",
            "It is powered by data and algorithms, but it doesn\u2019t learn from its mistakes",
            "It is powered by blockchain and it learns from its mistakes and its experiments"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It is powered by data and algorithms and it learns from its mistakes and experiments"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 206,
        "question": "What is the relationship between Amazon and open innovation?",
        "answers": [
            "Bezos has never been interested in open innovation",
            "Bezos has always been interested about it, but has never resorted to open innovation",
            "Amazon has started resorting to open innovation only in the last years, obtaining great results",
            "Amazon has always been oriented to open innovation, albeit with logic and results that have evolved over time"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Amazon has always been oriented to open innovation, albeit with logic and results that have evolved over time"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 207,
        "question": "Which digital business model(s) is (are) traceable to the step \u201cAmazon as an e-commerce and distributor\u201d?",
        "answers": [
            "Data-driven business model and platform business model",
            "Platform business model",
            "Smart factory business model",
            "Data-driven business model and servitization business model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Smart factory business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 208,
        "question": "Which digital business model(s) is (are) traceable to the step \u201cAmazon as a marketplace platform\u201d?",
        "answers": [
            "Data-driven business model and platform business model",
            "Platform business model",
            "Smart factory business model",
            "Data-driven business model and servitization business model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Platform business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 209,
        "question": "Which digital business model(s) is (are) traceable to the step \u201cAmazon as a service provider\u201d?",
        "answers": [
            "Data-driven business model and platform business model",
            "Platform business model",
            "Smart factory business model",
            "Data-driven business model and servitization business model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Data-driven business model and servitization business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 210,
        "question": "Which digital business model(s) is (are) traceable to the step \u201cAmazon as a phygital product/store platform\u201d?",
        "answers": [
            "Data-driven business model and platform business model",
            "Platform business model",
            "Smart factory business model",
            "Data-driven business model and servitization business model"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Data-driven business model and platform business model"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 211,
        "question": "What does it mean for Amazon to be an \u201cunstore\u201d?",
        "answers": [
            "It is bound by the traditional rules or customs of doing business in the commerce sector",
            "It is constrained by what is deemed best for the customer",
            "It has limitless shelf space and offers standardized services for each customer",
            "None of them"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "It is constrained by what is deemed best for the customer"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 212,
        "question": "Considering Amazon as an e-commerce and distributor:",
        "answers": [
            "There is an interconnection between its physical infrastructure and machines and their respective digital twins",
            "Its network extends upstream, next to its suppliers and partners, but not downstream",
            "There is an interconnection between its physical infrastructure and machines and its digital systems",
            "Its network extends downstream, including transport logistic operators and customers, but not upstream"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "There is an interconnection between its physical infrastructure and machines and its digital systems"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 213,
        "question": "Considering Amazon as a marketplace platform, the possibility for third-party retailers to sell their products on Amazon.com:",
        "answers": [
            "Allowed Amazon to appear as the digital store that could offer the widest selection of products at the most affordable price",
            "Reduced Amazon\u2019s product assortment because of substitution effect",
            "Was clearly the right choice and Immediately generated excitement among buyers",
            "Didn\u2019t involve competitors finalizing the sale in its place"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Allowed Amazon to appear as the digital store that could offer the widest selection of products at the most affordable pric"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 214,
        "question": "Considering Amazon as a service provider, the introduction of Amazon Web Services (AWS):",
        "answers": [
            "Has made Amazon the technology partner for the successful development of a digital business ecosystem based on cloud computing",
            "Allows Amazon to build strong and long-term relationships with customer",
            "Has created a very profitable business model and has given Amazon a leading role in the emergence of colud computing technology",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "All the answers are correct"
    },
    {
        "qnumber": 215,
        "question": "Considering Amazon as a phygital product/store platform, the devices introduced by Amazon:",
        "answers": [
            "Enable a software add-on business model",
            "Present a dual nature, digital-first and product-first",
            "Generate value by the systemic integration of the product and service components",
            "All the answers are correct"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "Generate value by the systemic integration of the product and service components"
    }
]
}